Mss.B.B445
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Salmon, M. R., 1939 February - 1940 February (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Graduate student at Columbia University looking to work under Max Bergmann.
  - Salzburg, Peter, 1937 July - 1939 September (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Salzburg, Peter
    Letters concerning employment for Salzburg. Salzburg writes to Max Bergmann seeking his help in finding a job in the United States.
  - Salzmann, Leo, 1934 May - 1940 December (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Salzmann, Leo
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Leo Salzmann.
  - Samples, 1943 March - 1946 October (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Samples
    Cross references and lists of chemical samples sent out of Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Sanders, Victor, 1942 January - February (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Sanders, Victor
    Letters concerning employment in the United States for Sanders. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Saxe, Sig, 1934 June - 1936 October (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Saxe, Sig
    Requests for reprints and samples from Max Bergmann.
  - Schales, Otto, 1939 February (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Schales, Otto
    Letter from Schales requesting a position in Max Bergmann's lab. Curriculum vitae and bibliography included.
  - Schlenk, Hermann, 1939 February (Box 19, Folder 10)
    Schlenk, Hermann
    Letter from Hermann Schlenk requesting a position in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Schlenk, Wilhelm, Jr., 1936 October (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Schlenk, Wilhelm, Jr.
    Letter from Wilhelm Schlenk requesting a position in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Schmidt, Carl L. A., 1934 May - 1942 November (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Schmidt, Carl L. A.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Carl Schmidt. Letters concerning a textbook to be written titled, "Introduction of the Chemistry of Amino Acids and Proteins." Requests fro reprints.
  - Schmidt, Erich, 1939 February - 1940 February (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Schmidt, Erich
    Letters discussing employment for Schmidt in the United States. Includes photocopies of affidavits for visa permits. Curriculum vitae.
  - Schmidt, Gerhard, 1935 October - 1943 October (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Schmidt, Gerhard
  - Schmitt, Francis O., No. 1, 1938 March - 1939 November (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Schmitt, Francis Otto, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Francis Schmitt. Requests for reprints and chemical samples. Letters of recommendation for an opening in Schmitt's lab. A copy of a paper written by Schmitt titled, "Electrolytes in the Axoplasm of the Giant Nerve Fibers of the Squid."
  - Schneider, F., 1934 April - 1935 June (Box 19, Folder 17)
    Schneider, F.
    Letter of advice from Max Bergmann regarding Schneider's dissertation.
  - Schmitt, Francis O., No. 2, 1941 March - 1944 June (Box 19, Folder 16)
    Schmitt, Francis O., No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Francis Schmitt. Letters concerning an experiment that Schmitt is conducting. Dinner invitations. Bergmann comments on a lecture given by Schmitt. Requests for chemical samples.
  - Schnier, R., 1934 November - 1939 October (Box 19, Folder 18)
    Schnier, R.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Schnier. Letters discussing articles in journals. Circulars adverstising new lab equipment.
  - Schocken, Klaus, 1934 November - 1935 October (Box 19, Folder 19)
    Schocken, Klaus
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Klaus Schocken.
  - Schoen, M., 1938 March - 1941 November (Box 19, Folder 20)
    Schoen, M.
    Letters concerning employment for Schoen in the United States.
  - Schoenheimer, Rudolph, 1938 November - 1940 December (Box 19, Folder 21)
    Schoenheimer, Rudolph
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Rudolph Schoenheimer. Letters of recommendation for a position in Dr. Kurt Goldenstein's lab. A letter from Schoenheimer seeking Bergmann's opinion on an article he wrote.
  - Science, 1934 May - 1939 January (Box 19, Folder 22)
    Science
    Miscellaneous material in regards to the journal "Science." Includes galley proofs, notes of thanks for Max Bergmann's contributions, and notes accompanying drafts.
  - Scientific Periodicals and Books, 1944 December (Box 19, Folder 23)
    Scientific Periodicals and Books
    A list of scientific periodicals and books for sale after the death of Max Bergmann.
  - Scudi, John V., 1938 September - November (Box 19, Folder 24)
    Scudi, John V.
    Letters discussing employment for John Scudi. Curriculum vitae, publication list, and photograph of Scudi included.
  - Selfhelp, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
    Selfhelp
    Cross references to other files in the collection regarding refugees.
  - Seligsberger, Ludwig, No. 1, 1941 October - 1942 November (Box 19, Folder 26)
    Seligsberger, Ludwig, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Ludwig Seligsberger. Letters discussing the work of both scientists. Letters discussing publications.
  - Seligsberger, Ludwig, No. 2, 1934 May - 1939 December (Box 19, Folder 27)
    Seligsberger, Ludwig, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Ludwig Seligsberger. Seligsberger writes Bergmann looking for employment in the United States.
  - Serine, 1941 June (Box 19, Folder 28)
    Serine
    A copy of an article written by Max Bergmann titled, "The Isolation of l-Serine from Silk-Fabric."
  - Shedlovsky, Theodore, 1941 October - 1942 May (Box 19, Folder 29)
    Shedlovsky, Theodore
    Correspondence concerning the Program Committee at the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Shriner, R. L., 1937 April - 1938 January (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Shriner, R. L.
    Correspondence in regards to a talk given by Max Bergmann at the "Seventh National Organic Chemistry Symposium."
  - Siegel, Fritz, 1939 December (Box 19, Folder 31)
    Siegel, Fritz
    Siegel writes to Max Bergmann seeking assistance finding employment in the United States.
  - Silk, undated (Box 19, Folder 32)
    Silk
  - Small, F. H., 1936 April - 1938 February (Box 19, Folder 32)
    Small, F. H.
    Small writes to Max Bergmann asking him to review several papers.
  - Small, Lyndon F., 1943 November (Box 19, Folder 33)
    Small, Lyndon F.
    Lyndon Small, the chairman for the canvassing committee for the Eli Lilly Award, writes to Max Bergmann for his recommendation of Joseph Fruton to be awarded the prize for 1944.
  - Smith, Edric B., No. 1, 1941 November - 1944 October (Box 19, Folder 34)
    Smith, Edric B., No. 1
    Miscellaneous letters from Edric Smith, business manager at the Rockefeller Institute, in regards to Institute policies and procedures, budgetary concerns, and other general business matters.
  - Smith, Edric B., No. 2, 1938 April - 1942 April (Box 19, Folder 35)
    Smith, Edric B., No. 2
  - Smith, Edric B., No. 3, 1934 June - 1937 November (Box 19, Folder 36)
    Smith, Edric, No. 3
  - Smith, Emil L., No. 1, 1942 January - 1944 November (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Smith, Emil L., No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Emil Smith. Letters regarding a mutual paper to be published.
  - Smith, Emil L., No. 2, 1940 September - November (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Smith, Emil L., No. 2
    Letters concerning a volunteer position in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Smithburn, Kenneth C., 1937 December - 1938 February (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Smithburn, Kenneth C.
    Correspondence reagarding a "Symposium on Proteins" held at the Rockefeller Institute in February 1938.
  - Societies, 1942 June - 1943 October (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Societies
    Invitations and programs for events held by several societies. Also cross references to other files in the collection.
  - Sollner, Karl, 1937 January - 1944 October (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Sollner, Karl
    General correspondence bewteen Max Bergmann and Karl Sollner. Early letters from Sollner requesting Bergmann's help in finding employment. Requests for reprints and chemical samples. Discussion on experiments. Notes of well wishes.
  - Solmssen, Ulrich, 1937 June - August (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Solmssen, Ulrich
    Correspondence concerning employment for Ulrich Solmssen. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Soviet Relations, 1941 December - 1943 October (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Soviet Relations
    Circulars from the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship Inc., the American Council On Soviet Relations, and the Ambijan Committe for Emergency Aid to the Soviet Union. Letters seeking donations from Max Bergmann.
  - Sperry, Warren M., 1938 November - 1943 November (Box 20, Folder 8)
    Sperry, Warren M.
    Letters regarding a postition in Max Bergmann's lab for Dr. Heinrich Waelsch. A letter to Sperry asking him to recommend Bergmann, Joseph Fruton, and William Howard Stein for membership in the Biochemical Society.
  - Spiegelberg, Flora, 1934 May - June (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Spiegelberg, Flora
    Letters discussing the details of a dinner invitation.
  - Spies, Thomas D., 1939 July - August (Box 20, Folder 10)
    Spies, Thomas D.
    Spies writes to Max Bergmann requesting information on Sidney W. Fox.
  - Springer, Julius, 1936 April - 1939 may (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Springer, Julius
    Orders for books.
  - Squibb, E R & Sons, 1937 March - 1943 September (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Squibb, E R & Sons
    Letters to Max Bergmann requesting a reference for Dr. Gertrude Berend. An invitation to the opening of the Squibb Institute for Medical Research. A letter from Max Bergmann requesting a copy of a bibliography from an article.
  - Sreenivasaya, M., 1935 May - 1939 March (Box 20, Folder 13)
    Sreenivasaya, M.
    A request for Max Bergmann to be a visiting professor of Biochemistry at the Indian Institute of Science.
  - Staff Meeting, 1940 January 26 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    Staff Meeting
    Notes from a staff meeting.
  - Stamm, Guido, 1940 January - 1941 September (Box 20, Folder 15)
    Stamm, Guido
    Correspondence concerning a year long collaboration between Guido Stamm and Max Bergmann at Bergmann's lab.
  - Stanley, Wendell M., 1937 April - 1940 June (Box 20, Folder 16)
    Stanley, Wendell M.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Wendell Stanley. Bergmann requests samples of tobacco mosaic virus and other chemicals. Stanley sends a note of congratulations to Bergmann on his appointment to the membership of the Rockefeller Institute.
  - G. E. Stechert and Company, 1940 November - 1945 June (Box 20, Folder 17)
    G. E. Stechert and Company
    Book sellers. Book lists for 1944. Orders of catalogs and books. List of second hand books Max Bergmann wishes to sell.
  - Stein, Fred M., 1942 June - 1944 January (Box 20, Folder 18)
    Stein, Fred M.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Fred Stein, of the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars. Stein sends Bergmann the Committees latest report and a list of names that Bergmann might be able to help find work for.
  - Stein, William H., No. 1, 1936 May - 1937 October (Box 20, Folder 19)
    Stein, William H., No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and William Stein. Several letters discussing different experiments.
  - Stein, William H., No. 2, 1943 May - 1947 February (Box 20, Folder 20)
    Stein, William H., No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and William Stein. Requests for reprints. Notes on experiments. Requests for chemical samples. Draft of an article by Stein and Bergmann. Office procedures and reprint list compiled by Stein after Bergmann's death.
  - Stein, William H., No. 3, 1939 August - 1944 August (Box 20, Folder 21)
    Stein, William H., No. 3
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and William Stein.
  - Steinberg, Robert A., 1940 May - November (Box 20, Folder 22)
    Steinberg, Robert A.
    Steinberg writes to Max Bergmann to discuss a technical problem with an experiement.
  - Steinherz, Dezsoe, 1939 April (Box 20, Folder 23)
    Steinherz, Dezsoe
    Letters concerning a patent for a particular method.
  - Stern, Dora, 1939 April - 1941 January (Box 20, Folder 24)
    Stern, Dora
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Dora Stern. Letters concerning employment for Stern. Bergmann refers her to the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars.
  - Stern, Egon, 1941 June (Box 20, Folder 25)
    Stern, Egon
    Correspondence concerning employment in the United States.
  - Stern, Karl, 1945 June (Box 20, Folder 26)
    Stern, Karl
    Letter to the office of Max Bergmann requesting chemical samples. Letter informing Stern of Bergmann's death.
  - Stern, Kurt G., 1936 November - 1942 February (Box 20, Folder 27)
    Stern, Kurt G.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Kurt G. Stern. Requests for reprints. Invitation to speak at an enzyme chemistry meeting at Yale.
  - Sternberg, William, 1939 March - April (Box 20, Folder 28)
    Sternberg, William
    Arrangements to meet with Max Bergmann.
  - Stewart, Florence M., 1941 April - 1944 March (Box 20, Folder 29)
    Stewart, Florence M.
    Correspondence regarding the Rockefeller Institute semi-annual reprint list.
  - Stiller, Eric, 1941 April - 1943 July (Box 20, Folder 30)
    Stiller, Eric
    Stiller writes to Max Bergmann concerning several experiments.
  - Stokes, J. L., 1944 May - June (Box 20, Folder 31)
    Stokes, J. L.
    Letters to Max Bergmann requesting protein samples.
  - Strauss, Edward, 1939 February (Box 20, Folder 32)
    Strauss, Edward
    Correspondence concerning employment for Edward Strauss. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Strode, George K., 1942 October (Box 20, Folder 33)
    Strode, George K.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and George Strode concerning the German development of lousicide.
  - Subscriptions, 1937 January - 1944 November (Box 20, Folder 34)
    Subscriptions
    Subscription notices to journals and societies.
  - Supplee, G. C., 1934 December - 1945 January (Box 20, Folder 35)
    Supplee, G. C.
    Max Bergmann writes to Supplee requesting a large supply of protein.
  - Swift, Homer F., 1937 December - 1943 April (Box 20, Folder 36)
    Swift, Homer F.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Homer Swift. Invitations to meetings and dinners.
  - Synthetical Laboratories, 1934 June - August (Box 20, Folder 37)
    Synthetical Laboratories
    Requests for chemicals, prices, and quotes.
  - T - Misc., No. 1, 1940 May - 1941 May (Box 20, Folder 38)
    T - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous correspondence.
  - T - Misc., No. 2, 1934 March - 1944 May (Box 20, Folder 39)
    T - Misc., No. 2
  - T - Misc., No. 3, 1934 July - 1943 August (Box 20, Folder 40)
    T - Misc., No. 3
  - Tandler, Rudolf, 1939 January - February (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Tandler, Rudolf
    Letters discussing employment for Tandler. Includes copies of two papers sent by Tandler to Bergmann.
  - Tanners' Council of America, 1932 - 1934 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Tanners' Council of America
    Bulletins for the Tanners' Council of America.
  - Tauber, Henry, 1935 October - 1947 August (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Tauber, Henry
    Requests for reprints from Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1938 September - 1943 September (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association
    Literature from the Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association.
  - Telegrams, 1942 February - 1944 June (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Telegrams
    General miscellaneous telegrams.
  - Teutsch, Ilse, 1939 February - 1940 June (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Teutsch, Ilse
    Correpondence between Max Bergmann and Ilse Teutsch. Teutsch writes to Bergmann seeking his help in bringing a Dr. Fritz Weinmann to the United States.
  - Thannhauser, S. J., 1941 March - 1944 January (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Thannhauser, S. J.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Thannhauser. Thannhauser asks Bergmann's advice on an experiment. Bergmann recommends chemists to work in Thannhauser's lab.
  - Thomas, Lloyd E., 1941 January - 1942 May (Box 21, Folder 8)
    Thomas, Lloyd E.
  - Tietzman, Josephine, 1941 May - 1944 August (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Tietzman, Josephine
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Josephine Tietzman. Includes a letter of recommendation written by Bergmann for Tietzman.
  - U - Misc., 1935 December - 1942 December (Box 21, Folder 10)
    U - Misc.
  - Uber, Fred M., 1940 September - 1943 September (Box 21, Folder 11)
    Uber, Fred M.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Fred Uber. Exchange of chemicals and reprints. Uber writes seeking information on Hermann Barschall. Bergmann recommends Walter Marx and H. M. Evans to work in Uber's lab.
  - Unemployed Scientists, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    Unemployed Scientists
    A list of unemployed scientists, mostly refugees.
  - United China Relief, 1941 November - 1943 November (Box 21, Folder 13)
    United China Relief
    Circulars, newspapers, and requests for donations.
  - United States, 1940 May - 1941 December (Box 21, Folder 14)
    United States
    Notices of government jobs.
  - Universities, 1937 December - 1944 August (Box 21, Folder 15)
    Universities
    Miscellaneous correspondence between Max Bergmann and officials from several different universities. Includes letters of reference and recommendation written by Max Bergmann.
  - University of Michigan, 1938 July (Box 21, Folder 16)
    University of Michigan
    A series of four lectures given by Max Bergmann at the University of Michigan.
  - Urey, Harold C., 1942 September (Box 21, Folder 17)
    Urey, Harold C.
    Max Bergmann writes to Urey requestiong information regarding Saul Soloway.
  - V - Misc., 1935 August - 1944 October (Box 21, Folder 18)
    V - Misc.
  - Van Slyke, Donald D., No. 1, 1934 Janaury - 1936 November (Box 21, Folder 19)
    Van Slyke, Donald D., No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Donald Van Slyke. Notes of congratulations to Bergmann for winning the Phillip A. Conne Gold Medal in 1936. Requests and thanks for reprints.
  - Van Slyke, Donald D., No. 2, 1938 October - 1944 October (Box 21, Folder 20)
    Van Slyke, Donald D., No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Donald Van Slyke. Requests for reprints. Dinner invitations. Notes of congratulations. Van Slyke writes to Bergmann wanting donations for the Committee for Medical Aid to China.
  - Van Slyke Apparatus, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
    Van Slyke Apparatus
    A series of charts for use with the apparatus.
  - Vickery, Hubert, No. 1, 1934 October - 1942 March (Box 21, Folder 22)
    Vickery, Hubert, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Hubert Vickery. Requests for reprints. Notes on experiments. References for Dr. Ruth E. L. Berggren.
  - Vickery, Hubert, No. 2, 1938 February - 1944 November (Box 21, Folder 23)
    Vickery, Hubert, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Hubert Vickery. Exchange of reprints. Vickery and Bergmann recommend Joseph Fruton for an Eli Lilly Award. Correspondence concerning various experiments. A notice informing Vickery of Bergmann's death.
  - Viobin Corporation, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    Viobin Corporation
    Circulars conataining examples of Viobin corn products.
  - Visitors, 1935 June - 1944 September (Box 21, Folder 25)
    Visitors
    Business cards of visitors who have visited Max Bergmann's lab at the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Voegelin, Charles, 1939 May - June (Box 21, Folder 26)
    Voegelin, Charles
    Correspondence concerning references for a postion in Voegelin's lab.
  - Von Der Osten, Anna L., 1942 October - 1943 October (Box 21, Folder 27)
    Von Der Osten, Anna L.
    Letters asking for the names and addresses of all the scientific staff working in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Von Gutfeld, Fritz, 1942 February - 1943 August (Box 21, Folder 28)
    Von Gutfeld, Fritz
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Fritz Von Gutfield.
  - Vonk, H. J., 1937 December - 1938 May (Box 21, Folder 29)
    Vonk, H. J.
    Requests for chemical samples.
  - W - Misc., No. 1, 1934 September - 1944 January (Box 21, Folder 30)
    W - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous correspondence. Exchange of reprints. Requests for chemical samples. Personal letters.
  - W - Misc., No. 2, 1935 March - 1948 January (Box 21, Folder 31)
    W - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous correspondence. Requests for reprints. Letters of recommendation. Correpondence concerning employment in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - W - Misc., No. 3, 1937 April - 1943 September (Box 22, Folder 1)
    W - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous correspondence. Requests for chemical samples. Letters of introduction. Letters concerning experiments.
  - W - Misc., No. 4, 1934 September - 1944 March (Box 22, Folder 2)
    W - Misc., No. 4
    General miscellaneous correspondence. Requests for reprints. Invitations to speaking engagements. Letters of recommendation.
  - W - Misc., No. 5, 1934 September - 1944 April (Box 22, Folder 3)
    W - Misc., No. 5
    General miscellaneous correspondence. Letters concerning employment for organic chemists. Exchange of reprints.
  - Waelsch, Heinrich, 1938 November - 1939 January (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Waelsch, Heinrich
    Letters concerning employment for Heinrich Waelsch. Curriculum vitae and publications list included.
  - Wagreich, Harry, 1938 June - 1942 June (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Wagreich, Harry
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Harry Wagreich. Wagreich writes to Bergmann concerning several problems with a protein experiments. Requests for chemical samples. Exchange of reprints. Wagreich expresses his interest in collaborating with Bergmann on National Defense Research Projects.
  - Waksman, Selman A., 1934 March - May (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Waksman, Selman A.
    Correspondence concerning a job in the United States for Carl Neuberg.
  - Wallerstein, Leo, No. 1, 1936 November - 1941 May (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Wallerstein, Leo, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Leo Wallerstein. Letters discussing experiments. Requests for chemical samples. Correspondence concerning refugee scientists.
  - Wallerstein, Leo, No. 2, 1934 December - 1937 December (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Wallerstein, Leo, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Leo Wallerstein. Exchange of chemical samples. Requests for reprints. Discussion of experimental procedures. Letters concerning refugee scientists. A list of Max Bergmann's United States patents.
  - Wallerstein Laboratory No. 1, 1938 Janauary - 1939 December (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Wallerstein Laboratory No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and the Wallerstein Laboratory. Communication is mainly between Bergmann and Leo Wallerstein. Discussion of refugee scientists, reprints, copies of lectures, and requests for chemicals and apparatus.
  - Wallerstein Laboratory No. 2, 1940 February - 1941 December (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Wallerstein Laboratory No. 2
  - Wallerstein Laboratory No. 3, 1942 Janauary - 1942 June (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Wallerstein Laboratory No. 3
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and the Wallerstein Laboratory. Communication is mainly between Bergmann and Leo Wallerstein. Exchange of reprints. Letters concerning experiments. Requests for chemical samples.
  - Wallerstein Laboratory No. 4, 1942 July - 1944 May (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Wallerstein Laboratory No. 4
  - Walter, George, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Walter, George
    Curriculum vitae and letters of recommendation.
  - Walti, Alphonse, 1940 February - 1941 March (Box 22, Folder 14)
    Walti, Alphonse
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Alphonse Walti concerning the transaction of chemicals.
  - Wassermann, Michael, 1939 February - 1944 September (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Wassermann, Michael
    Correspondence concerning employment for Wassermann.
  - Weaver, Warren, 1936 September (Box 22, Folder 16)
    Weaver, Warren